<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-10T15:48:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">JDA Labs</title><subtitle>JDA Labs contributes in crafting tomorrow's supply chain. We are a collective of eclectic and passionate people specializing in Data Science, Design and Technology.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Research on Gamification in Warehouses</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/warehouse-gamification_research" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research on Gamification in Warehouses" /><published>2018-09-10T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/warehouse-gamification_research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/warehouse-gamification_research">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In partnership with Tech&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;Lab, we conducted a research on the impact of gamified interfaces on the engagement and performance of employees in a warehouse.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to to determine what effect the gamification of warehouse employee’s interface
has on his/her engagement and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does gamification improve employee performance?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does gamification improve employee engagement?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of gamification method (self-set or assigned goals) leads to better performance?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of gamification method (self-set or assigned goals) leads to higher engagement?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gamification is defined as the “use of game design elements in non-game contexts”. In other words, gamification employs the engaging nature of elements used in video games to create engagement in another context. Some of the common elements used in gamified interfaces are points, levels, goal-setting, feedback, badges and leaderboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, workplace gamification has become more prevalent and has been proposed as solution to this lack of engagement (Zichermann &amp;amp; Cunningham, 2011; Google Trends, 2012). Indeed, only 13% of employees worldwide consider themselves as engaged in their work (Mann &amp;amp;Harter, 2016). 
The use of gamification has been widespread across various domains and contexts. For example, within education/schools to increase learning outcomes (Garcia et al., 2018; Gooch, 2016), to within health to increase adherence to and enjoyment of rehabilitation exercises (Jacobs et al., 2013), to within a driving context to increase safety (Steinberger et al., 2017). However, there have been relatively few examples of attempting to integrate gamification in warehouse employees’ interface, a domain that has mainly focused on optimizing the warehousing tasks, as opposed to the human performing it (Small, 2010). The lack of emphasis on the human aspect offers a great opportunity for increasing employee engagement and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current study will focus on two of gamified elements: goal-setting and feedback.
The experiment will also allow for the examination of the physiological mechanisms (Electrocardiography (ECG) and electrodermal activity (EDA) sensors and electroencephalography (EEG)) by which gamification affects performance. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research demonstrated the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gamification improved employee performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results have shown that gamification (of either kind) results in increased performance in
terms of time taken to complete the task. No difference has been found in number of errors.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Gamification improved employee engagement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results show that gamification (of either kind) results in more engagement, in both measured
facets of perceived engagement (cognitive and emotional). 
Results show that gamification (of either kind) results in more physiological
engagement. Affective intensity, measured by EDA, is an indicator of emotional engagement.
Most participants also mentioned that they felt more motivated/engaged when the had a goal of
any kind. It made the task less tedious and gave them a challenge. No participant preferred
the condition without gamification.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Company set goals improve performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results show that assigned goals result in better performance, both in terms of time and errors.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Assigned goals improve engagement but may not be sustainable on the long term&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants do not report any difference in emotional or cognitive engagement between both
gamified conditions. The physiological data, however, tells a different story. Assigned goals
generate more arousal and high Heart Rate and thus, more possibility emotional engagement.
However, it is not possible to exclude that Heart Rate increases due to the fact that participants are performing the task faster. Therefore, we cannot exclude the possibility that this condition
may not be sustainable over a day period as it could lead to fatigue and exhaustion. When
looking at the interview data, it is hard to differentiate which condition was the most
preferred. Condition preference seemed to result from personal taste. 
9 of the 21 participants preferred the assigned goal condition. Some preferred this condition
because they took the goal more seriously (because it came from a “company”) which made
them more motivated to reach the goal. Others preferred this condition because they did not
have to decide which goal to choose, the objective was clear and unambiguous. 12 of the 21
preferred the self-set goal conditions. Some mentioned that they preferred this condition
because it made them feel more motivated because the goal seemed to come from
themselves. Others preferred this condition because they could choose a goal based on how
they are feeling that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to correlate those results to the type of gaming personalities of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study also provided some insights on the usability of the wearable device’s interface that the participants used during the experimentation and how we could improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This research was presented at NeuroIS Retreat 2018. The paper is available in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neurois.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Preprint-Proceedings-Part-2.pdf#page=39&quot;&gt;proceeding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In partnership with Tech3Lab, we conducted a research on the impact of gamified interfaces on the engagement and performance of employees in a warehouse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blockchain for Supply Chain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/blockchain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchain for Supply Chain" /><published>2018-09-10T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20180910/blockchain">&lt;h1 id=&quot;brief&quot;&gt;Brief&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, we started to explore blockchain technologies as a mechanism to support and manage transactions in a digital supply chain. We initially identified four use-case categories where a blockchain could be leveraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close business collaboration
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Shared data between producers, distributors and retailers (de-centralized, immutable)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End-to-end Traceability
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Product provenance (organic, fair-trade)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Food safety and regulation / Cold chain compliance, …&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disintermediation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eliminate margin-hurting participants (agents, wholesalers, certification bodies…)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digitalization and automation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Smart supply chain, digital documents, Internet of Thing (IoT)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the initial use cases are not related to cryptocurrencies, we decided to focus on enterprise blockchain frameworks and we selected Hyperledger Fabric for our first prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain Labs prototype is about product traceability in the supply chain. A blockchain is used to identify multiple participants in a business network (farmers, manufacturers, distributors, stores) and to manage transactions between them. For a specific product (Orange Juice), the application captures and logs transactions between supply chain stakeholders.Tthe system provides a digital proof of ownership over time (where is the product, who owns it).
As blockchain information will never be modified or deleted, the system supports supply chain traceability and audit scenarios. For a specific bottle of orange juice, it is possible to identify all the supply chain participants, back to the farmers who provided the oranges.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Brief In January 2018, we started to explore blockchain technologies as a mechanism to support and manage transactions in a digital supply chain. We initially identified four use-case categories where a blockchain could be leveraged. Close business collaboration Shared data between producers, distributors and retailers (de-centralized, immutable) End-to-end Traceability Product provenance (organic, fair-trade) Food safety and regulation / Cold chain compliance, … Disintermediation Eliminate margin-hurting participants (agents, wholesalers, certification bodies…) Digitalization and automation Smart supply chain, digital documents, Internet of Thing (IoT)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Research on Recommendation Agents</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20180720/recommendation_agents_research" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research on Recommendation Agents" /><published>2018-07-20T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20180720/recommendation_agents_research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20180720/recommendation_agents_research">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In partnership with Tech&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;Lab, we conducted a research on the impact of the visual representation of a recommendation agent on users’ perceptions and behaviors.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to determine the extent to which the visual representations of a recommendation agent influence the perceptions and behaviors of retail professionals in assortment planning decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do professionals trust the recommendations?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What information help them trust the RA?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would they let the RA take decisions?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) based recommendation agents (RA) can help planners make better decisions by processing a large quantity of decision relevant information. Research on user-RA interactions show that users benefit from RA, but that there are some challenges to their adoption. For instance, RA adoption can only happen if users trust the RA. Thus, this study investigates how the richness of the information provided by an RA and the effort necessary to reach this information influence users’ perceptions and usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A within-subject lab experiment was conducted with 20 participants. We tested 3 different conditions (tasks) with 2 scenarios. We gathered psychometric measures through a questionnaire and behavioral measures through an Eye tracking device (Smart Eye Pro).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results suggest that perceptions toward the RA (trust, credibility, and satisfaction) are influenced by the RA information richness, but not by the effort needed to reach this information. In addition to contributing to HCI literature, the findings have implications for the design of better AI-based RA systems.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed trends in the Retails Professionals’ perceptions and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perceptions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The effort required to access the additional information does not have an impact on users’ perceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information richness positively affects users’ perceptions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users are more willing to adopt the RA as a decision aid than as a delegated agent for all three conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behaviors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users are referring more to the additional information at the beginning of their decision-making process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When additional information is available, users consult more frequently the information easily accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research was presented at CHI 2018. The paper is available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3188639#.W1YvudjZSWM.link&quot;&gt;ACM Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In partnership with Tech3Lab, we conducted a research on the impact of the visual representation of a recommendation agent on users’ perceptions and behaviors.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/recomm_agent" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Control Tower</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20171008/dct" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Control Tower" /><published>2017-10-08T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-08T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20171008/dct</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20171008/dct">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify data to help users understand complex situations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage Artificial Intelligence to propose sets of solutions to specific problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gather input from numerous sources (social media, weather, traffic, local events, stock markets, etc) to improve quality of predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dispatch action items to other system to implement selected solution and monitor progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Simplify data to help users understand complex situations. Leverage Artificial Intelligence to propose sets of solutions to specific problems. Gather input from numerous sources (social media, weather, traffic, local events, stock markets, etc) to improve quality of predictions. Dispatch action items to other system to implement selected solution and monitor progress.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tire loading and AR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20170809/tire-loading" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tire loading and AR" /><published>2017-08-09T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-09T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20170809/tire-loading</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20170809/tire-loading">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner of the 2017 Canadian Operational Research Society Practice Prize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was derived from a real-life loading problem arising at one of the leading tire manufacturer. Because there exists a wide range of agricultural tires, each shipment is unique and container loading plans have to be determined on a per case basis. From a theoretical perspective, dealing with circular shapes differs significantly from classical rectangular box packing problems. The team studied several solution approaches and eventually proposed an innovative and efficient method. They highlighted the parameters that were key to the success of this method. Insights gain from this research study have been used in TMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year the Canadian Operational Research Society conducts a competition on the practice of operational research to recognize the challenging application of the OR approach to the solution of applied problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:33.33333333333333% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BXYaCA8A5tv/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by JDA Labs (@jdalabsmtl)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-08-04T18:07:33+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 4, 2017 at 11:07am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, this prize was awarded to a team with Philippe Grangier, Marc Brisson, Louis-Martin Rousseau (JDA Labs) and John Ye (TMS Team) together with Michel Gendreau (Ecole Polytechnique de Montréal, Canada) and Fabien Lehuédé (IMT Atlantique, France). The team received this award at the 21st Conference of the International Federation of Operational Research Societies (IFORS) held in Quebec City in July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixed Reality Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the research code has been integrated in another JDA Labs project that focuses on 3D vizualization of instruction-based tasks (featured in project video.) This proved to be useful in expanding the scope of the 3D instruction interface, &lt;a href=&quot;/project/20170731/instructar&quot;&gt;instructAR&lt;/a&gt;, which was originally designed for pallet building.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Winner of the 2017 Canadian Operational Research Society Practice Prize</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">instructAR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/instructar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="instructAR" /><published>2017-07-31T12:55:26-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-31T12:55:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/instructar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/instructar">&lt;p&gt;InstructAR is a set of visualization tools to overlay information directly onto a real world workspace allowing us to guide workers through complex, sometimes non-intuitive tasks simply and accurately. We are currently experimenting with applications of this idea to pallet and truck loading since loading instructions can become complex and loading accuracy is important for optimized pallet builds and truck loading plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our pallet loading application we project the location of the next box to load directly onto the pallet itself using the Hololens mixed reality headset. The user advances through the steps by using air taps or voice command. For demo purposes the app has three pre-built pallet configurations but we imagine in the future that it could obtain pallet instructions from an optimizer running on a server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;/project/20170809/tire-loading&quot;&gt;Tire loading&lt;/a&gt; application has a similar interface but takes its loading plan from a real optimization algorithm created by the data science team at JDA Labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also experimented with visualizing the instructions using spatial AR, i.e. by projecting the instructions onto a pallet using a digital projector. This has the advantage of not requiring a bulky headset but has other design considerations that need to be worked out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">InstructAR is a set of visualization tools to overlay information directly onto a real world workspace allowing us to guide workers through complex, sometimes non-intuitive tasks simply and accurately. We are currently experimenting with applications of this idea to pallet and truck loading since loading instructions can become complex and loading accuracy is important for optimized pallet builds and truck loading plans.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pepper: Shoe Assistant</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/pepper" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pepper: Shoe Assistant" /><published>2017-07-31T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-31T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/pepper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/20170731/pepper">&lt;p&gt;Late in 2016, we were asked to reflect on how we could leverage humanoid robots in retail environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem-space&quot;&gt;Problem Space&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came up with a proposal that tackles a problem observed in shoe stores/departments: The employees need to check the inventory for the customer.
The greatest distinction between shoes and other products is that, for shoes, a store will typically display only a floor model and does not give clear visibility over the availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to experiment offloading part of this responsibility from the employees to a robot, in order allow more time to the employees to do what they are good at – to help customers choose shoes that fits their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory visibility and task dispatch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pepper can check the store inventory for particular sizes. If it is available, a task will be sent out to an employee in the back store or any other system able to fetch products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offers alternatives, if not available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the size is not available, Pepper can identify alternatives for customers instead of plainly cutting short the customer’s desire try/buy a pair of shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plugged with a model that identifies similar products, it could propose other options that have high probability of appeal the customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check other stores + NFC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another alternative is to check other nearby stores for requested product availability. If interested the customer can tap his NFC enabled phone on the sensor to get a reservation confirmation and direction to the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RFID/NFC capabilities were added by us using a raspberry pi that communicates to Pepper. Pepper can instruct our sensor to communicate information via NFC or get information whenever there is a RFID tag that is read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete transaction online&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the product is available online, the customer could use NFC to either order it directly with Pepper or continue the transaction in his phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalized interaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using NFC, a customer can scan his phone to communicate some information about his preferences. In our demo, the customer share his usual shoe size to Pepper. In the next iterations we could also share product interest and history of purchase. This would help Pepper propose relevant products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Late in 2016, we were asked to reflect on how we could leverage humanoid robots in retail environments.</summary></entry></feed>